Yuliia Tkachenko

FRONT END DEVELOPER

+1 (778) 957 63 12 | ecspetra@gmail.com | Vancouver, Canada

www.yuliia-tkachenko.dev | linkedin.com/in/tkachenko-yuliia-v | github.com/ecspetra

SUMMARY

I offer over 6 years of commercial work experience in Web Development: 2,5 years as a Software Engineer and 4 years as a UI/UX designer. During this time, I have contributed to creating and developing 20+ projects of various sizes and complexity. I have established myself as a software developer with a passion for creating efficient and innovative solutions to complex problems.

WORK EXPERIENCE

D3 Security | Vancouver, Canada

05.2024 - 11.2024

Software Engineer

- Contributed to developing the D3 Smart SOAR platform to automate incident response and improve cybersecurity workflows
- Fixed 50+ bugs across multiple project modules, significantly improving product stability and performance
- Developed and launched 2 major features, enhancing core functionality and user engagement
- Implemented inline editing in data tables, boosting user efficiency and improving the overall user experience
- Utilized my UI/UX design expertise to enhance visuals and improve the logic and usability of 2 key project pages
- Refactored codebase on both frontend and backend, improving performance and reducing client-side processing time by 20%, while ensuring more predictable and reliable functionality

Tech stack: React, JavaScript, C#, SQL, HTML, SASS, CSS, JQuery Kendo UI, Ant Design, Git

Swivl | Menlo Park, USA

12.2021 - 08.2023

Markup (Front End) Developer

- Contributed to developing a productivity tool for improving focus and optimizing the learning experience
- Implemented 20+ reusable SCSS components that increased the development speed by half and improved code readability
- Developed the project interface with a responsive layout, ensuring 100% accessibility
- Played a proactive role in discussions aimed at improving the project
- Suggested the idea of images and SVG file compression that led to a 20% faster page load
- Developed **3 landing pages** using React as a framework
- Created and maintained 10+ WordPress pages to enhance product sales
- Built 4 email templates for marketing campaigns

Tech stack: React, TypeScript, HTML, SASS, Git, WordPress

Livelib | Mariupol, Ukraine

Front End Developer 08.2021 – 12.2021

- Worked on a high-loaded project with over 3 million monthly users
- Integrated SASS technology into the project to optimize style usage, resulting in more efficient and manageable markup implementation
- Refactored legacy styles and markup moving them into reusable Pug components, resulting in a significant decrease in code duplication
- Achieved a **30**% **performance improvement** by optimizing complex CSS files, as reported by web-monitoring tools
- Developed 2 commercial advertising projects, 3 landing pages and a corporate wiki

Tech stack: JavaScript, JQuery, HTML, CSS, SASS, Git

UI/UX Designer 07.2017 – 02.2021

- Worked as UI/UX designer on a social network, created as a platform for famous book writers
- Developed design for 600+ banners, 20+ landing pages, 4 corporate websites, 10+ email templates
- Created an advertising project template, speeding up the development process by 80%

Tech stack: Photoshop, Illustrator, Figma

Mentor

• Provided mentorship at an IT school for children and developed instructional materials for introducing them to programming and UI/UX design

EDUCATION

Master of Computer Science | Pryazovskyi State Technical University, Ukraine

09.2017 - 12.2018

SKILLS

React, JavaScript, TypeScript, Next.js, Redux, Redux Toolkit, C#, Git, HTML, CSS, SASS, Tailwind, Bootstrap, JQuery, WordPress, JIRA, Photoshop, Figma, Illustrator, Firebase, Design Patterns